Muhammed Fairoos N.M.

Nerattichalil house, Mankadavu, Kozhikode 673645

② fairoos.me

 \square fairoosnm123@gmail.com

? fairoos-nm

 \Box +918281927861

SUMMARY

A result-driven, articulate, and analytical Software Developer with a demonstrated history of working in Python, 2 Plus years of IT experience, and 1 Plus year of the non-IT sector. Served as Team Member on multiple web application development projects for various clients like JrnyOn, Mathrubhumi, True Link Financial, Christus, Etc.

SKILLS

Frameworks/Libraries Django, Scrapy, Beautiful Soup, Boto-3, Docker, Celery, DRF, Bootstrap

OS Linux, Windows

Languages Python, JS, SQL, Bash, Embedded C

Database RDBMS, BigQuery
Website (coded) HTML5, CSS and SCSS

Tools Emacs, Pytest, Postman, Django Debug Toolbar

Typesetting Document Latex Version Control Git

EXPERIENCE

Tarams Technologies

Bengaluru, India

Software Engineer

MAY 2019 - PRESENT

o Designed and built Performance-Oriented Web applications and support existing products.

Tech Genius Robotics and Technology Ventures LLP

Kozhikode, India

Embedded Hardware Enginee

APR 2018 - JAN 2019

- o Built basic Embedded projects using Arduino and Raspberry Pi.
- o Took sessions in embedded systems and robotics for Atal Tinkering Labs (ATL).

Model Engineering and Technical Institute

Wandoor, India

Instructor in Electronics Engineering

JUNE 2017 - MARCH 2018

- Took sessions in Basic Electronics.
- Worked as Lab attender in Advance Electronics Lab.

PROJECTS

ISEFARPRO

Django, PostgreSQL, Azure, SendGrid, JS, HTML

A recommendation platform for Hospitals to get recommendations based on patient's current health and medications, the platform helps to effectively track cost savings with a multi-role-based dashboard and having responsive front-end with multi-language support.

JrnyOn

Django, PostgreSQL, React Native, DRF

The platform was built to provide an app-based travel service. That helps to plan and book group vacation tours all over the world. Users were able to create trips and invite like-minded co-trippers to the app for booking a trip.

True Link Financial

Scrapy, Beautiful Soup, Sqlite3, Postman, Bash

A data sourcing project by web scraping profile details of people and organizations from multiple websites related to the notary, financial, and health care using Scrapy and Beautiful Soup. The collected information is stored in the CSV format.

Mathrubhumi Billing App

 $Django,\ MySQL,\ Pandas$

A web-based billing application for Mathrubhumi. As a part of version enhancement, worked with integrations of e-invoice system API with app and automation of email invoice.

Song-lyrics-classifier

Python, pytest, Beautiful Soup

Implementation of Naive Bayes classifier to predict artists using the trained model. Automated lyrics downloading part of different artists from a website called MetroLyrics using beautiful soup and implemented classification from scratch using python.

EDUCATION

Programmer Mentoring Course

Kozhikode, Kerala

The Lycaeum

2019

Diploma in Engineering

Thirurangadi, Kerala

AKNM Government Polytechnic College(Board of Technical Education)

2014-17